日本語字幕仕上げ：miraku  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
Tsubaki!
椿！
いけ～ 椿!
Go, Tsubaki!
He's fast!
Wind? Or is it a torpedo?
風…
というか　突風？
Hiraga!
ヒラガ！
行ける…
This will work!
Okay!
よし！
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
For the right! Hold on tight!
for the right
hold on tight
My story...
my story…
forever
Forever...
Alright!
よっしゃ～！
That's a good spot!
いい位置だ！
Nice one, Tsubaki!
でかした　椿！
よっしゃ～！胸張れよ　椿！
Nice! Be proud of that, Tsubaki!
お前の足とスタミナで もぎ取った　フリーキックだ！
Your speed and stamina have earned us that free kick!
椿…椿…
I'm taking out Hiraga and Hauer.
We are going to hold on to our one-goal lead for the remaining 10 minutes.
Don't get me wrong,
we're not changing our team's philosophy yet.
It only means that we've come to a stage...
where it's possible for us to experience games like this.
After all, the season is far from over.
Katsuragi and Minami.
カツラギと　ミナミ
葛城と南！
Go get Katsuragi and Minami!
Got it!
はい！
今の言葉に ウソはないだろうけど
I'm sure he wasn't lying,
ダルファー監督にしては珍しい
but considering it's Dulfer, it's quite unexpected.
自分の哲学を排してまで
He's scrapping his philosophy in the hope of securing victory today.
貪欲に 今日の勝利を取りにいくのか
And the one who pushed him to such an extent is...
監督の勝負師としての意地　それを 引き出したのは
間違いなく…
Focus! Make sure to leave no gaps!
集中　集中！
お前ら　詰めていけよ！
He's mysterious indeed, Takeshi Tatsumi.
不思議な男だ…
達海　猛
サカ　右だ！もう１歩右！　そう！
Saka, to the right! Another step to the right! That's good!
赤崎が蹴るぞ！
Akasaki will shoot! His shots are really accurate today!
あいつのキックの精度　今日　冴えてるぞ！
冴えてる？
Accurate? The one who's really accurate is...
冴えてるのは…
Man, this is tough.
いや～　参ったよ
When I first heard about this plan, I thought it sounded fun.
作戦を初めて聞いた時は面白いと思ったんだけどね
My pass completion rate goes down...
わざと半端な所に出しているとね
...when I intentionally put them in weird places.
僕のパス成功率が下がってしまうんだよ
As I thought, Gino wasn't having an off day.
やはりジーノは不調ではなかった…
違う！　ジーノだ　イマさん！
No! It's Gino, Ima!
He's the one in top form today!
今日　調子がいいのは　ヤツだ！
He'll definitely take the shot!
ここで絶対蹴ってくる！
え？でも　ボールを置いたのは…
But the one who put down the ball is...
それが向こうのねらいだってんだよ！
That's what they want us to think!
クッ！　この程度の事で惑わされるとは…
I can't believe he's falling for it.
どっちにせよ直接狙ってくるだろう
Either way, they'll probably aim for the goal directly.
I can react in time if I predict their moves.
コースさえ絞っておけば反応できる
平賀　代えるか？
Are you subbing Hiraga off?
追いつくには ここを頂くしかねえぞ
We definitely have to score from this then.
赤崎じゃない！
It's not Akasaki!
ジーノだ！
It's Gino!
I've decided, ever since I saw your face in the second half,
後半　顔を見た時から 決めてたよ
you're the only one for this situation.
こういう場面で合わせるなら 君しかいないってね
YEAH!
よっしゃ～！
We caught up!
同点！同点だ～！
We are level now!
Good job, Sugie!
スギ　よくやった！
Nice one, Sugie!
ナイスっス　スギさん！
お疲れっス
Good job.
お疲れ
Job well done.
お疲れさま
お疲れ！
Good job, Sugie, Akasaki.
スギ　赤崎
Wow, I'm surprised.
いやぁ 参った
ビックリしたよ
They actually caught up... I thought it'd be impossible.
まさか本当に追いつくとはねぇ
俺　絶対に無理だと 思ってたのになぁ
やるね　ＥＴＵ
Not bad, ETU.
What kind of attitude is that?
どういう態度よ ＥＴＵの番記者でしょ　あんた
Aren't you ETU's reporter?
But these series of substitutions...
で　この同じタイミングでの交代
At first glance, it looks like both managers are revealing their trumps cards,
一見両監督とも勝負に出て
カードを使い切ったようにも 見えるけど
but the difference in momentum is evident.
勢いの差は歴然だな
皮肉なものですね
Ironic indeed, eh?
ここにきて　ＥＴＵは 借りを返さんとばかりの 攻めの態勢に出て
Now, ETU is going all out to turn the game,
圧倒的に ゲームを支配していた大阪が
while Osaka, who was dominating the match in the first half,
is now enforcing their defense to preserve a draw.
終盤は　引き分け狙いの 守りに入った
１枚目のカード
The first card: By sending in the defensive Ootomo,
守備的な大友を入れた時点で
it acted as a signal to the Osaka's players to hang on to their lead.
大阪の選手に課せられたのは 逃げ切ること
それが追いつかれた今
Now that they've been cornered,
急に はい　みんなで攻めろとは簡単には　いかないもの
going on the offensive again is not going to work out.
As I thought, the decisive moment here...
やはり大きかったのは
...was Dulfer's hesitation to take out Hiraga.
ダルファー監督の 平賀交代に対する躊躇か
If that was what he intended to do,
もし　これが　ねらいだったのなら
達海　猛が作戦を立てる上で矛先を向けたのは
then his plan wasn't aiming at taking down Kubota or Hiraga,
実は　窪田でも平賀でもなく
but at Dulfer's strategy itself.
大阪のベンチワーク ダルファー監督の采配そのもの
Oh, I might be able to write an article with this.
あっ！　これで１本　記事書けそう
Though it might all be retrospective.
あくまで結果論かもしれないけど
But, you know...
あ～あ　でもなぁ さすがに逆転は無理だろうな
I really doubt they can manage an upset.
いいかげんにしなさいよ　あんた！
Cut it out already!
I can understand the decision to bring on Hotta and Miyano,
堀田と宮野を入れる意味も 分かるんだけど
なんでフォワード代えねえかな
but why don't they swap forwards instead?
That would have threatened their opponent more.
そのほうが相手も怖えだろうに
Damn, I guess I won't play today.
チッ　今日は出番なしかよ
I thought that I'd get to play since Natsuki was not playing well,
夏木が　ポカばっかやってっから
すぐ呼ばれると思ったけど
なんか調子 取り戻しやがったしな　あいつ
but I guess he got his form back.
なんだなんだ　あの野郎
What the hell? He's out of breath.
息上がってんじゃねえかよ
Geez...
ったく！
Do your job, since you're on the field!
やるならやれってんだよ
ピッチに残ってんならよ
Tan and Hotta, also Miyano...
丹さんに堀田さん
あと宮野
I knew it! We've already used up our substitutions.
やっぱりそうだ
ウチは交代３枚使った
That means...
てことは
I made it through...
俺　残った
I wasn't subbed out!
交代させられなかった
やったあ！
Alright! I'm playing the whole match, an important one at that!
こんな大事な試合で フル出場だ！
って　何考えてんだ　俺のバカ～！
Wait, what am I thinking about?! I'm such an idiot!
This isn't the time to be happy about something like this!
今　そんな事で喜んでる場合かよ！
世良！
Sera! We're going to move Tsubaki up further up,
椿を１列前に上げるから
お前は夏木の すぐ下でやれ！
so you go play right behind Natsuki!
オ　オス！
Got it!
There's not much time left.
残り時間は　もう少ない
Who knows how many chances we'll get.
チャンスだって　あと何度あるか 分からない
I've got to do it! This is when forwards stand up to be counted!
やるんだ こういう時こそ　フォワードが
Shit, don't get tired now! It's stupid!
クソ～ バテんな俺
カッコ悪いぞ
Why does the manager use someone like me?
なんで監督は こんな俺を使うんだろう
Hey!
What the hell, Osaka?!
おいおい なんだよ大阪！
同点のくせに 引いてんじゃねえよ
Stop wasting time just to get a draw!
Indeed. That's cheap!
そうだ　ずるいぞ！
ズルではないけど　コンニャロ～！
It's not cheating, but you suck!
But, you know?
でもさあ　ＥＴＵって なんか逆転のイメージないよな
ETU doesn't have a history of causing upsets, right?
Hm, I guess so...
あ　そういや…
It often ends in a draw.
よくて引き分け止まり
その上　向こうのディフェンス陣は 寺内とか小室とか代表選手いるし
And on top of that, their defense has Terauchi and Komura who are both national players.
確かに
Ugh, that's true.
でも　こっちも２点 返してるじゃん
But we came back from two goals down!
そうなんだけどさ…
That's true,
but if they employ an ultra-defensive strategy...
それが ガッチリ守りに入られるとさ…
か～っ　いよいよ時間が なくなってきましたね
Argh, we're running out of time.
One more! One more! Can we do it, Manager?
もう１点！　もう１点！
いけますかね　監督？
My plan was to come back from just a one-goal deficit to win at 2-1,
俺のプランでは
大阪は１点に抑えて２対１で 勝つつもりだったからなぁ
３点目って言われてもなぁ…
so I really don't know about the 3rd goal.
D-Don't you have anything up your sleeve?
なっ　な　なんかないんですか？
ここまで　いい勢いできてるのに！
We've built up so much momentum!
What's with you? I'm not god, you know!
なんだよ　松ちゃん  人のこと　何でも屋みたいに
期待はしてるよ
But I am counting on him.
Him?
期待？
このチームに足りない 最後の粘り強さ
His tenacity is the last strength that ETU lacks.
それを変えてくれるって期待
え？　誰のことですか？
Huh? Who are you talking about?
裏狙ってくるぞ！
They're coming from the back! Watch out for their counter!
カウンター警戒しろ！
No! A counter!
カウンター！
おっしゃ～！ 待ってたで　シムさん！
Alright! I've been waiting for this!
Did you really think I'd let you do as you want?
最後の最後で テメエらなんかに　やらせるかよ！
Damn!
Hey!
１回戻しなよ　カッタン
Pass it back for now!
Alright!
よし！
Yes!
よ～し！
Nice, Murakoshi!
ナイス　村越！
ははっ　面白えな
This is funny.
Huh? What is, Kudo?
はい？　何がっスか？ 久堂さん
いや　なに
Well, it's just...
It's still a draw, yet there's a sense of urgency in Osaka's play.
同じスコアだってのに
大阪のほうが 焦ってんなと思ってさ
逆にＥＴＵの連中のほうが
On the other hand, the ETU players are all riled up.
この土壇場で　いい顔してやがる
Or rather, they might be really enjoying this game.
というよりか
楽しめて やがんのかもな　このゲームを
時間な～い！
We don't have time! Send it to the center!
どんどん中に入れてけ～！
Nice, Gino!
ナイス　ジーノ！
Natsuki, sink it in!
決めろ　夏木～！
ぐわ～高さじゃ勝てねえ
He just can't win in the air.
やはり　ナッツは やめておけばよかった
As I thought, I shouldn't have passed it to Natsu.
Yeah, Sera!
うおっ！　世良～！
Damn it!
クッソ～
We're pushing so hard!
こっちがガンガン攻めてんのに！
Osaka's defense is really tight!
やっぱり大阪の守り　堅え！
Geez, that was so close!
あ～っ！　惜しかったな　今の
I guess a situation like that is hard for someone small like Sera.
やはり　ああいう場面
ガタイのない世良には 酷ですかね～
That's not true.
全くもって　んな事ない
Not true at all.
We've got 4 minutes of injury time! We can do this!
ロスタイム４分　いけるぞ！
Attack, guys!
攻めろ　お前ら！
Who the hell is ETU anyway?!
ＥＴＵが　なんやっちゅうねん！
格の違い見せつけたれや～！
Show them that we're in a different league!
Damn it! Focus!
クソッ！
もっと集中しろ　俺！
I have to get to the ball first before some big guy runs into me.
でかい相手に当たられる前に ボールに追いつかねえと
I'm not physically strong...
俺　フィジカル弱えんだから
フィジカル弱いどころか
I don't have much technique either.
テクニックもないんだから
I'm also short and stupid.
その上　身長もないし
頭も悪い
I basically lack in every aspect that is required of a professional.
俺には　ないもんばっかりだ
プロ選手に必要なもんが
I don't have any talent!
俺に　才能なんてもんはない
確かに世良は　体格的には 恵まれてないのかもしれない
It's true that Sera is not gifted physically.
Huh?
But, you know,
でもね
世良みたいな選手ってのは 自分に何ができないかを知ってる
players like Sera know what they can't do.
That means...
それはつまり　自分にできる 限られた事が分かってるって事だ
...they know of their limitations.
That's why they won't hesitate on the field.
だからピッチで迷わない
選択肢が ない分
Since they don't have much options, they react much faster.
プレー中の判断が早い
Just like the one before.
さっきの場面もそう
He was able to compete for the loose ball because he reacted quickly to it.
こぼれ球に いち早く反応してた世良だから
競り合うところまでいけたんだ
なるほど…
I see...
Players like him are probably born with an inferiority complex.
恐らく世良みたいな選手は
劣等感から始まってる
They keep eliminating things they can't do...
できない事を消去法でそぎ落とし
and only work on the things they can do.
できる事だけを磨いてプレーしてる
There is nothing that won't shine if you polish it enough.
磨いて輝かないものなんてない
だから期待するんだ　俺は
That's why I'm hoping...
そういうヤツが才能ってもんを凌駕すんのを
that someone like him will surpass those with talent.
そういう選手の頑張りが
The effort of a player like him will make the team stronger.
チームを強くするんだ
Osaka's defense is focused.
大阪の守備は 集中している
崩すにはＥＴＵ側に　何かアイデアがないと
ETU will have to think of something to break it down.
Something... unexpected.
何か　意外性のある…
Nice cut, Koshi!
ナイスカット　コシさん！
Go ahead!
前だ　前！
Murakoshi is going to the front!
村越そのまま来た～！
Get on your marks!
マークつけ！　マーク！
Watch out in the center! Block his course!
来い！
Come! Focus on me!
こっちに釣られろ！
Good pass!
うまい！
Okay!
よし！
Shoot, Tsubaki!
打て～　椿～！
惜しい～！
So close!
I don't have any talent.
俺には才能なんてもんはない
Go!
プロでやれてるだけで奇跡的だ
It's a miracle that I can play on the pro level.
But...
けど　監督は こんな俺を使ってくれてる
The manager is letting someone like me play.
Maybe then...
それなら
Maybe believing in a player like myself is fine after all!
信じてみても いいかもしれない
A player... just like me!
俺が 俺っていう選手のことを！
SERA!
世良！！！
決めた～！
He did it!
このチビ野郎！　とんでもねえ！
You idiot! You did the impossible!
とんでもねえ事したな　お前
Amazing! You were amazing, Sera!
すごい！ すごいっス　世良さん！
It's an upset!
逆転だ！　逆転！
Yeah!
I did it! I did it!
やった…
やった！
この土壇場で
I did it right at the death!
I'm... I'm amazing! I did it, everyone!
俺…　俺って…
俺って　スゲ～！
やったぞ　みんな～！
Well played, ETU!
お　終わった…
It's... It's over.
ってことは…
That means we've... won!
か…　か…　勝った
よっしゃ～！　勝った～！
Alright! We won! It's a huge upset!
３対２の大逆転だ！
ハハハ　参ったね　こりゃ
Impressive!
今期負けなしで　ぶっちぎってた 大阪相手に
They've obtained a big scalp in the form of the once-invincible Osaka.
大金星かよ
Unbelievable... Is this really ETU?
信じられねえな
これが本当に　あのＥＴＵかよ
変わったんですよ　ＥＴＵは
ETU have changed.
Huh?
そろそろ受け入れましょうよ 山井さん
It's time you accepted that, Yamai.
ＥＴＵは　きっとこれから 台風の目になってくれますよ
ETU will surely be the center of the storm.
And I have my eyes on him,
そして　そのＥＴＵの中で
核となって チームを引っ張っていってくれる 選手…
the one who'll become their core and pull the team together.
私の目には…
万歳！　万歳！　万歳！
世良～！　よく決めた！
Sera! Good job!
Nice goal, Sera!
ナイスゴール世良！
うわ～　ありがとうサポーター！
Thank you, fans! I love you all!
大好きだ　みんな～！
なあ世良
Hey, Sera!
お前さあ　ゴール決めたらバク宙するとか 言ってなかったか？
Didn't you say that you'd do a backflip if you scored?
He's right. Maybe this goal is worth doing it.
確かに このゴールって そのぐらいの価値あるかも
今やってもいいっスかね？
C-Can I do it now?
えっ　今？
Now?
未完成だから佐野さん支えて
Don't expect much though since it's not completed yet.
み…　未完成？
Not completed?
Okay, I'll do it!
よし　いくぞ～！
Hey, man-of-the-match.
よう　マンオブザマッチ
Shit, it hurts!
あ…　いっ　痛え～！
って　堺さん
S-Sakai.
お前さあ
You know, you were kicked hard when you scored that goal.
ゴールの時 思いっ切り肩蹴られてたじゃねえか
くだらねえパフォーマンスなんかして
If your silly performance results in further injuries, what will happen?
体壊したら　どうすんだよ
You still don't know what it means to a pro, do you?
相変わらず　プロの 自覚ねえのな　お前
I got scolded already...
いきなり怒られた
でもよ…
But, you know...
蹴られるかもと 分かってて飛び込んだ
Diving in, knowing that you'll be kicked...
バカじゃねえと できない事だ
Only idiots could pull that off.
お前はフォワードとしての自覚はある
You've realized what it truly means to be a forward.
そこだけは認めてやるよ
I'll give you credit for that.
ボールってのはな　世良
You know, the ball...
しぶとく あきらめないヤツの前に必ず転がってくるもんなんだ
...will always roll towards the person who never gives up.
堺さん！
Sakai!
What?
本当に転がってきました！
The ball really came!
あざ～っす！
Thanks!
いっ　痛え～！
What was that for?! And I just praised you too...
何すんだテメエ！
せっかく褒めてやったのに！
I'm sorry! You got it all wrong, it's a misunderstanding!
あ～っ　すいません堺さん！
違うんス　誤解っス！
What the hell are you talking about?!
何が誤解なんだよ！
誤解なんすよ　おれは　あの　いや　僕は感謝…
Sonoda...
Yes, Manager?
I am extremely frustrated right now... especially with myself.
This would not have happened if I was more decisive.
But, you know...
At the same time, I feel really satisfied.
I understand. It was a good game fought at the very highest level.
The next time we meet, it'll be at our home in Osaka,
Takeshi Tatsumi.
どうでしたか？
How was it? Was Dulfer spewing a bunch of excuses?
ダルファー監督は 負け惜しみとか言ってましたか？
No, he just glared fiercely at me.
ううん　スゲエにらまれた
次やる時も　めんどくさそうだ
Seems like our next match will be a bother again.
ああいう 負けず嫌いの監督は
Man, those managers who just refuse to lose...
でも　そうこなくっちゃね
But it has to be like that,
or it wouldn't be fun defeating them.
倒しがいってもんがない
I'm looking forward to the next match.
楽しみだぜ…
次の対戦が
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say “never look back”
I'll say 「never look back」
oikaze o matte
追い風を待って
Wait for the tailwind
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
そうchanceをのがすなら
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
no tears,Yes Let it go！
Get tough! Get tough!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
限界追い越せ
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
あすは見えない だから
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough!
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough! Get tough!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
共に乗り越えて 行け
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on! Go on!
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Stay cool!
We'll go!
yosoku dekinai dakara
予測できないだから
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
止められない
Akasaki has been called up to the team that'll represent Japan in the Olympics.
I've never heard about this!
Hey! We're going to make curry for 100 people,
so those who are free, help out!